<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Chaos Monkey</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-01-04T18:40:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Installing the KeePass Password Manager</title><link href="/installing-the-keepass-password-manager.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-23T15:02:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-04T18:40:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Phil Grimes</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-23:/installing-the-keepass-password-manager.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I want to walk through installing the KeePass password manager on Windows 10. This post will explore downloading, installing, and first steps to using a local password manager. The end result, for those who follow these steps, will be an encrypted password generation and storage mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setting Up KeePass …&lt;/h1&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I want to walk through installing the KeePass password manager on Windows 10. This post will explore downloading, installing, and first steps to using a local password manager. The end result, for those who follow these steps, will be an encrypted password generation and storage mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setting Up KeePass&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download KeePass&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in the process is downloading the installer. From the KeePass download page &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;https://keepass.info/download.html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_, there are options for both the installer and the portable package. While this post will be focused around installing the software on Windows 10, the portable option provides a good solution for users who need their passwords on multiple machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="KeePass Download Page" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP1_KeePass_Download_Page.png" title="KeePass Download Page"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose the installer and then save the file to disk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Save Installer" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP2_Save_File.png" title="Save Installer"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once downloaded, navigate in Explorer to wherever the file was saved. Usually, this is in C:\Users\$USER\Downloads. Double clicking the installer will launch the process. After Windows User Access Control confirms permission to proceed, the KeePass installer will launch. The following series of images illustrates the install process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing KeePass&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, select the install language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Select Language" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP3_Choose_Language.png" title="Select Language"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The license agreement is next. Be sure to read this before selecting "I accept the agreement", which is required in order to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="License Agreement" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP4_License_Agreement.png" title="License Agreement"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally don't mess with the install path, but if you have a desire, the next dialogue allows for definition of where KeePass will be installed on the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Install Path" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP5_Choose_Install_Location.png" title="Install Path"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another area that I typically don't mess with, the component selection dialogue lets users take more control over what components of KeePass are installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Component Selection" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP6_Component_Selection.png" title="Component Selection"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet another menu that requires no changes, the options pictured below ensure that KeePass recognizes the .kdbx file extension, as well as letting the user decide if a desktop and/or Quick Launch shortcut should be created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Additional Tasks" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP7_Additional_Tasks.png" title="Additional Tasks"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the options configured, take a moment to look over the install configuration before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Review Install" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP8_Review_Install.png" title="Review Install"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we're off to the races! In a few moments KeePass will be installed on the local system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Installing" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP9_Installing.png" title="Installing"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installation completes, launching KeePass will take us into the next steps to configure a password database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Launch KeePass" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP10_Launch_KeePass.png" title="Launch KeePass"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Using KeePass&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Launch the Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you accepted the install defaults, there is an icon on the desktop. Otherwise find the launcher in the start menu and KeePass walks users through the basic steps of setting up a database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New Database" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP11_New_Database.png" title="New Database"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the path and file name that will become the password database file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Set Database Location" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP12_Database_Location.png" title="Set Database Location"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to define the master password. This is the one password which users need to remember to access all the other passwords. Generally, I encourage users to use a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;passphrase &amp;lt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Passphrase&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; rather than a password, for increased security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Set Master Password" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP13_Configure_Master_Password.png" title="Set Master Password"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presuming both entries match, selecting "OK" will take us into some additional database settings. Again, since we're just covering the basics of KeePass, I won't be covering these today, but I encourage users to explore these other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Additional DB Settings" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP14_Additional_Database_Settings.png" title="Additional DB Settings"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last step in the setup is to print the KeePass Emergency Sheet. Print this off, fill out the details, and keep it safe as this will contain the details to gain access, should someone need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Emergency Sheet" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP15_Emergency_Sheet.png" title="Emergency Sheet"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, we're presented with the KeePass interface. In a later post, we'll work with creating, editing, and using various entries, and how to put KeePass to work generating, and protecting, your passwords from prying eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="KeePass Interface" src="../images/installing_keepass/KP16_KeePass_Interface.png" title="KeePass Interface"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several default entries and categories within a default KeePass database. I highly recommend exploring the entries that are available, learning the options, and making some mistakes with passwords that don't matter before you start entering passwords on which you depend into KeePass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've followed along at home, we've successfully installed, configured, and started using the KeePass password manager. While this post was written to demonstrate the process on a Windows 10 machine, KeePass also runs on Linux and Mac. In the next post, I'll cover some notes on general usage of KeePass and the use of online alternatives. The goal here is to get readers to understand the benefits of using a password manager, and to illustrate the ease with which they can be implemented. I hope you've found this post to be informative and I appreciate the time you've taken to read it. Remember that we live in a hostile world and it is important to take measures to protect yourself!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Security"></category></entry><entry><title>Self Doxing: Loose Lips Sink Ships</title><link href="/self-doxing-loose-lips-sink-ships.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-04T14:22:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-07-04T14:22:00-05:00</updated><author><name>phillipGrimes</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-04:/self-doxing-loose-lips-sink-ships.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For anyone who spends any time reading my content, you may remember a recent post that outlines my thoughts on the general basics of Operational Security. A well timed &lt;code&gt;tweet &amp;lt;https://twitter.com/cokebottle/status/1012345863371395072&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\ last week, sparked by this &lt;code&gt;article &amp;lt;https://medium.com/@cosmin.ciobanu/my-top-5-opsec-rules-for-airport-lounges-7c0a48d4c09b&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, kicked off …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For anyone who spends any time reading my content, you may remember a recent post that outlines my thoughts on the general basics of Operational Security. A well timed &lt;code&gt;tweet &amp;lt;https://twitter.com/cokebottle/status/1012345863371395072&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\ last week, sparked by this &lt;code&gt;article &amp;lt;https://medium.com/@cosmin.ciobanu/my-top-5-opsec-rules-for-airport-lounges-7c0a48d4c09b&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, kicked off some interesting conversations around the topic which resulted in the series of thoughts that sparked what you're reading now. During the interactions on Twitter, one &lt;code&gt;tweet &amp;lt;https://twitter.com/spyblog/status/1012442709917880320&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__ in particular hit on several areas that I observe to be blatantly prevalent as I travel, work in the field, or observe people in general daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these were called out by others during the conversation, and I have had the (mis)fortune of running into some of them recently, I figured I'd expound on the topics. In my normal fashion, I thought some anecdotes could help drive the visibility up a bit and hopefully get some of you thinking a little differently about how you handle yourselves in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What is "Doxing"?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a little background. Somewhere along the line "doxing" became a recognized form of internet attack. Basically, this tactic requires the attacker(s) to scour internet resources to gather information on a targeted individual, and then broadcasting personal or private information about that person. While the point of this article is not to go in-depth into the world of doxing, some high profile examples are outlined on the &lt;code&gt;Wikipedia page &amp;lt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doxing&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__ covering the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, attackers will use the collected information to put pressure on targets, or to put them at risk in the most severe circumstances. While this most often is the result of actions taken by attackers against us, all too often people fall victim to "self-doxing". In these instances, inattention to details or surroundings falsely convince a person that they are in a safe place to divulge certain information. All of these vectors are viable and often employed 'in the wild'. As an attacker, I exercise these skills without even thinking about it. Here is my take on the subject:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shoulder surfing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sitting aboard a flight recently, exit row aisle seat. I had been drawn to one particular individual who'd caught my attention through his generally boisterous nature during the boarding process. His holier-than-thou arrogance dripped off him, much like the aroma of the Tommy cologne he must've bathed in that morning. My eyes, closed as usual to appreciate the sensation of takeoff, opened when the flight attendant came over the PA with an annoyed tone. Her reminder to remain seated through the ascent was prompted by Mr. Important as he was standing in the aisle 2 rows ahead of me, digging his laptop from his belongings in the storage compartment above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he settled back into his seat, I couldn't help myself but to get a peek at what was so pressing. In the hour that followed, I caught sight of documents his company surely wouldn't want outsiders to see. I didn't take photos for proof but I'm pretty sure capturing these documents would have been fairly easy to do. I also saw other juicy tidbits like contact information for others within Mr. Important's company. Were I a bad guy, I could have leveraged the information here in a social engineering campaign to gain access to more sensitive information, and potentially unauthorized access into the company itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's wise to be mindful of your surroundings, especially when traveling. You never know who's watching so exposing sensitive data should always be considered a risk in public. These things can usually wait until you're in a private place where prying eyes are not a concern. However, if you must touch sensitive data in public, use a &lt;code&gt;privacy filter &amp;lt;https://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Daps&amp;amp;field-keywords=laptop+privacy+screen&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__ to reduce exposure to onlookers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Passive conversation listening&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into two separate instances on the same trip recently, where the information divulged in conversation provided me with enough information to identify the individuals, and gather significant pieces of private information about them, to make a significant impact upon their personal lives. I wanted to share these experiences here in hopes that we can reduce the number of times so much information is divulged in such a short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mary Loves to Fly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd never met Mary before. Nothing about her caught my attention. She was already in the middle seat, one row behind me, when I settled into mine. As the plane filled, conversations rambled as they do, and when Mary's travel neighbors settled in, she  chatted up a storm with Lucy in the window seat next to her. Now I am usually a pretty passive listener, a skill honed over a lifetime which lets me parse conversations and pick up on valuable tidbits. It's quite nice for drowning out the general drivel of small talk while still letting me tune in when the conversation turns juicy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes into Mary's conversation with Lucy and I was gleaning bits and pieces of data that officially had me tuned in. Mary had given up her last name within minutes as well as her husband's name, he was sitting up in first class but she thought the upgrade was not worth the cost, and the names of their 3 kids who were waiting for them on the other side of the flight. By the time we touched down I knew cites of residence, places of employment, and names. With a little OSINT gathering, there was enough public record and social media interaction to provide me with a full profile of all 5 members of this family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alexis and Her Lexus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this same business trip, I was out to dinner at a local establishment. I sat at the bar and soaked up the atmosphere of the locals. 3 middle-aged men were at one corner of the bar sharing all kinds of tall tales, and taking their opportunities to hit on the young bartender, Alexis. Through the conversations they'd strike up with her, I learned she was a very proud owner of a Lexus RC, she was somewhat of a gym rat, and she once threw a full bottle of wine at an ex-boyfriend's head in a rage after finding out he cheated on her. Oh, and her last name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was already in the mindset of the effects of this information leakage, and so I did a little more digging and was again able to gather some pretty deep detail on this subject, just from the couple hours of conversation I listened into at the bar one evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With cases like the murder of Kenichiro Okamoto fresh in our minds, we have to realize that oversharing can be deadly. Sure, this is an extreme case but people don't realize how much information they leak on a regular basis. Stop talking about your children in so much detail with strangers. Don't be so comfortable to divulge details of where you work with someone you've just met - let along in the open air of an airplane with countless unknown listeners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dumpster diving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old adage rings true. One's trash really can be treasure to another! The information discarded into the trash can often be used to the advantage of a threat actor. Think about what you're getting rid of and how it might be used in the hands of some nefarious evil doer. As much as we'd like to think it won't happen to us, the chances are ever increasing that someone will act upon a crime of opportunity and make use of data if it's easily accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Public computers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm always surprised by the number of people I see who are still using shared computers. At the library, in the airport, and most often at hotels, people log into these shared machines for many reasons. I don't have much to offer here because I strongly recommend bringing your own device to access data when on the road. But if you must use a shared machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to delete cookie from the web browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete any files downloaded to the machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log out of EVERYTHING&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unattended devices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is another vector that just boggles my mind. Why, in today's hostile world, do people ever find it appropriate to leave their belongings unattended? I can't comprehend this logic. Even the cheapest MP3 player can be left alone and someone will take it simply because they can! People aren't nice. If you have something of any value, they're likely to want it for their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture you're in a parking lot, standing between 2 cars among a sea of others. 1/2 mile from anyone else with no surveillance. One car is locked and has a $100 bill sitting on the passenger seat. The other, windows down and unlocked, with a $5 in the cup holder. The chances are great that the $5 gets stolen more often than the $100 simply because of availability and ease of access. Make yourself and easy target and you make yourself a definite target.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Security"></category></entry><entry><title>OpSec in the Real World</title><link href="/real-world-opsec.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-28T18:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-04-28T18:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Phil Grimes</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-28:/real-world-opsec.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Operations Security&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is OpSec?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operations Security (OpSec) is the action of protecting information which might be used against one in a hostile encounter. OpSec forces a person, or organization, to perform threat modeling to determine potential vulnerabilities which might be exposed to adversaries and establish controls aimed at anticipating …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Operations Security&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is OpSec?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operations Security (OpSec) is the action of protecting information which might be used against one in a hostile encounter. OpSec forces a person, or organization, to perform threat modeling to determine potential vulnerabilities which might be exposed to adversaries and establish controls aimed at anticipating and defending possible attacks. Identifying attack surfaces and hardening them reduces risk and increases the difficulty an adversary faces in launching a successful attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“All warfare is based on deception. Hence, when able to attack, we must seem unable; when using our forces, we must seem inactive; when we are near, we must make the enemy believe we are far away; when far away, we must make him believe we are near.”  - Sun Tzu&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why OpSec&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to put my tin foil hat on for a moment to explain why OpSec matters. It is a harsh, cold world out there today and adversaries are everywhere. In a world that is constantly connected, where people share and over share everything, it's important that we're taking steps to protect ourselves, our data, and our friends/family. It can be something as simple as thoughtlessly sharing a photo to Facebook. Without thinking, you could expose someone to risk, There could be a stalker out there just waiting for information that could lead them to their prey. A Facebook group I belong to recently proved this threat as someone posted a photo in the group which exposed the license plate of another person who happened to be trying to escape an abusive spouse. Thankfully, the victim was gone before anything bad could happen but this mishap did put a dangerous person on the trail of someone they had been trying to find for nearly a year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sad fact of the matter is that there are so many bad situations we can find ourselves in today that makes OpSec more important than ever before. Keeping data safe means implementing consistent OpSec practices. My hope in writing this is that you'll think about your own operations security and will find ways to make changes that make you and your data more secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to OpSec?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating an effective OpSec program requires 5 steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Identify Critical Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critical information is a specific fact related to intentions, capabilities, or activities that could be used by adversaries in an attack. If Critical Information is obtained, the adversary would be able to impact the mission. The first step of the OpSec process is developing a Critical Information List (CIL) which defines any sensitive data which might be targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Limitations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of organizational risk and corporate espionage, learning the limitations of a partner or competitor could be invaluable. Learning what cannot be done is just as valuable as knowing what can. For a hostile threat agent to understand the limitations of a target&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Operation Plans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting visibility into planning operations poses a significant risk to both organizational \ &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;\ personal OPSEC. Attacks against operational plans include the who, what, when, and where components of the planning phases and can wreak havoc upon the forward momentum of operational plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007, stolen email accounts were worth anywhere from $4-$30. In 2008, prices fluctuated between $0.10 and $100. Compare this to 2009, when the price hovered between $1 and $20. Today, you can get 1,000 stolen email accounts for $0.50 to $10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit card information, on the other hand, has not depreciated in recent years. In 2007, credit cards advertised around $0.40 to $20 per record. Sale price would depend on factors such as the brand of card, the country of origin, how much metadata is provided, volume of purchase, and how recently the card data was obtained. In 2008, the average asking price for credit card data, according to my research, was slightly higher--$0.06 to $30--and later in the year it rose to from $0.85 to $30. Today, prices for stolen credit card records fluctuate between $0.10 and $20 per record. In general, credit card data prices have fallen slightly over the last few years, especially in cases where cyber criminals trade in volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where we saw healthcare records fetch $200-$500 for a single record in 2015, today prices are more in the range of $1.50-10 depending on the type of data and who's buying it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analyze Threats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With critical information identified, we now have something to protect. The next step is to determine the individuals or groups that represent a threat. There may be multiple adversaries, and different pieces of information may be targeted by different groups. In this stage, the capabilities, use for the information, determination and resources must also be analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analyze Vulnerabilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability analysis is one of the most challenging pieces of the OpSec puzzle. Basic vulnerability exists in innocent day to day tasks like conversations or phone calls in public or posts on social networking sites. But society has become more reliant on technology and a complacency has put us in the position of exposing our email conversations and web pages which can provide insight for a threat agent. In the most extreme cases, communication intercepts and espionage may come into play. Each level presents it's own risk and has it's own consequences. This is why &lt;code&gt;threat modeling &amp;lt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Threat_model&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__ is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Assess the Risks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, planners analyze the vulnerabilities identified in the previous action and identify possible OpSec measures for each vulnerability. Second, specific OpSec measures are selected for execution based upon a risk assessment done by the commander and staff. Risk is calculated based on the probability of Critical Information release and the impact if such as release occurs. Probability is further subdivided into the level of threat and the level of vulnerability. The core premise of the subdivision is that the probability of compromise is greatest when the threat is very capable and dedicated, while friendly organizations are simultaneously exposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Apply Countermeasures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Protected communications&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement controls over your personal communications. Use encryption wherever possible. Email can be encrypted using PGP. Text messages and mobile phone calls can be encrypted with services like Wire and Signal respectively. If you have a service you're using, there is probably a way to encrypt the data. Learn how and make it happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Protected Web Browsing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern web browsers offer methods to force the use of HTTPS while browsing. One way to accomplish this is with the use of browser plugins or extensions Adding this functionality to your browser will force encryption to be used during browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Physical Controls&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpSec doesn't solely apply to the internet, there are many concerns in the physical world too. While you operate in daily life, there are some considerations to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be alert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be suspicious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be aware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, consider the threat when you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to strangers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disclose in public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these present their own unique risks to personal OpSec and should be addressed to reduce the risk of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpSec is a necessity for anyone who has anything sensitive that needs to be kept confidential. Obscuring information, skewing facts, and offering misinformation can all be useful in protecting personal operations. Making sure to be consistent in these practices will eliminate the likelihood that information gets leaked to unauthorized parties, reducing the overall attack surface. Protect yourself out there- no one's going to do it for you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Security"></category></entry><entry><title>Breaking into Offensive Security</title><link href="/breaking-into-offensive-security.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-18T13:56:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-18T13:56:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Phil Grimes</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-03-18:/breaking-into-offensive-security.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's been a lot of talk around this topic lately. As I've been working to solidify my team's bond, I also have the challenge of helping those interested in getting involved in the offensive security world. This quest has helped me identify some things you might consider when trying to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's been a lot of talk around this topic lately. As I've been working to solidify my team's bond, I also have the challenge of helping those interested in getting involved in the offensive security world. This quest has helped me identify some things you might consider when trying to break into offensive security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Things to consider&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Have a well rounded knowledge of "advanced fundamentals"&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to sort out basic permission issues or understanding general functionality of major operating systems are not part of offensive security. However, understanding intricacies within operating systems and troubleshooting problems on the fly are.  Operators encounter countless complications in the field and rarely are they basic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those considering a career in offensive security should have a solid understanding of a wide range of technical topics. A successful attacker doesn't necessarily know all the answers, but definitely takes the time to learn as much about the fundamentals of a target as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Find your niche&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's important to know a little bit about everything, but it's equally important to find a specialty. Offensive security teams are often built around the strengths of the members. Members are often selected when engagements arise that require additional skills being added to the bench. Depending on the service offering of the team(s) you're involved with, bringing relevant expertise to the table is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal passions lie in social engineering and physical security. Other members  of my team are stronger in other areas than I. In the field, weather operating alone or as a unit, we rely on each other for help. Knowing the strengths and weaknesses of the membership, proper preparation, and thorough documentation all allow the team to tailor to the engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Know how to think, research, and study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An offensive security operator doesn't know everything about all the things.  Successful operators know how to profile and research a target and study the engagement in preparation. Additionally, they're also able to think their way through unforeseen circumstances and overcome adversity in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how accurate the profile, no matter how much intelligence has been gathered in preparation, problems and unexpected situations are inevitable in the field. Operators must be prepared for everything and still be able to think their way through the myriad of things that can go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be hungry for knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to want to learn. Everyone wants to be a hacker, to be Neo but not everyone wants to put in the work to bend the spoon. Someone wiser than I once said it takes 10,000 hours to become an expert at something. If you're only learning during the 8-5, that's roughly a 5 year path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't get lazy. Complacence is one of the biggest challenges to offensive security operators. They end up thinking they know it all and stop chasing the dragon, or they burn out along the journey. All too often, offensive security operatives fall prey to the latter, but the former is just as dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Have a strong work ethic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offensive security teams typically operate based upon the needs of the engagement. if that means working late nights, early morning, or weekends, then we work when there is work to be done. As a team, members need to be available whenever the engagement requires. It's important that operators are prepared to be dedicated to the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't as bad as it sounds. Learning the work/life balance, and learning how to work remotely, come with the territory. My team is expected to be available when it matters but they've also mastered the art of global availability. Weather it means fielding social engineering calls from the beach or conducting a vulnerability assessment from the audience of a school play, successful operators manage the demand of the workload while still trying to maintain a life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fourth quarter is the exception to this point. During fourth quarter, offensive security operators should expect to be running full bore with little room to breathe. The cyclical nature of fiscal business means that this is inevitable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be flexible&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Field Marshal Helmuth Karl Bernhard Graf von Moltke  once said "no plan of operations extends with any certainty beyond the first contact with the main hostile force."  Nowhere is that more true in the field of offensive security. Neither scope nor plan nor backup plan nor change order can account for the infinite number and combination of things that can go wrong in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offensive security operators need to accept this and be able to adapt, and overcome, in the field. While process and procedure are important in business, flexibility during an engagement is vital to operational success. The objective is what matters, the means do not- as long as they're within the rules of engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Take notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, offensive security is still a business. We must be able to prove what we do (and don't do), and we have to turn all the data into some actionable data that the client can use after. Successful operators live, and die, by their documentation. Not only for self reference, but the team should be able to pick up notes from other members and run with an engagement, if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documenting the engagement as it happens, especially when milestones or objectives are met, are vital to keeping accurate record of what happened. The more data that gets collected during the engagement, the more detailed and accurate the reporting and debriefing will be. However you decide to do it, take good notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't be afraid to make mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offensive security is a kludge of computer science, performance art, and voodoo. Much of the information exists in available documentation but there is much more to be written. And even when we think we've covered it all, there will still be niches and nuances and caveats that can't be accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be willing to take calculated, educated risks in the field. Realizing the objectives are what matter, operators need to be willing and able to take some creative freedoms in the field. This also means facing the consequences of those actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Own your attitude&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of my favorite movies, Training Day, Jake Hoyt (Ethan Hawk) talks about how you can only control your smiles and cries. In the field, attitude and response to adversity are two  of the very few things an offensive security operator can control. It's important to maintain this control and to remember that clients are looking to us as experts. If they see us responding poorly or carrying the dead weight of negativity, it will most certainly effect their overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't let the little things get to you. Realize that we live in imperfect chaos and the chances of anything going the way we want it to is highly unlikely, bordering on impossible. The successful offensive security operator maintains composure in the face of frustrating circumstances. The information security community is small and professional reputation is fragile. If the time comes that you're struggling to stay positive, keep your head held high and remember how hard you worked to get where you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't forget the soft skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work with computers because I really don't like people. On the same hand, it's important that an offensive security operator be able to interact with people effectively when deployed on an engagement. At the end of the day, the client is expecting a positive experience. The more pleasant a team makes it, and presuming quality work is submitted, the more likely they are to come back for repeat business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The offensive security operator is burdened with the responsibility of taking a mass of data, and an often unpleasant message, to a client in a manner which they understand and can relate to. This translation process, in my opinion at least, is one of the single most important components of a successful engagement. Without making the data  actionable for the client, the value in the service is diminished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Advice from a perpetual noob&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sad truth is that not everyone is cut out to do every job. While I will always advocate for everyone having an opportunity to try out for their dream job, it's an indisputable fact that not everyone makes the cut to play in the NFL or to act in a Hollywood film. You have to be more than just "computer literate" to make the cut on an offensive security team. If you're not striving for absolute excellence, you'll be swimming in an endless stream of mediocrity. I believe anyone reading this has the ability to reach the goal of becoming an offensive security operator. Having the drive, however is a different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my final thought, I want to stress that there is more to being an offensive security operator than just breaking things. In the field we are regularly placed in delicate environments with exposure to sensitive data. Morals and ethics are values of paramount importance to the offensive security operator. Degradation of these values may lead to loss of freedom in extreme case, but it will most certainly result in damage to the professional image of an operator. Reputation takes years to build but only moments to damage, and repair is long and tedious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you working to break into offensive security, I hope these tidbits offer you a little insight into my perspective into the consulting world. As a team leader and mentor, I wish you the best along your journey. As a fellow hacker, I look forward to learning with you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Career"></category></entry><entry><title>New Year, New Vulnerabilities</title><link href="/new-year-new-vulnerabilities.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-05T12:19:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-05T12:19:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Phil Grimes</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-01-05:/new-year-new-vulnerabilities.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, we got to ring in the new year with some major excitement, haven't we? 2018 has met us with a nasty 1-2 punch combination, no doubt! First, the exposure of a vulnerability that effects &lt;code&gt;millions of GPS tracking devices &amp;lt;https://www.csoonline.com/article/3245312/security/gps-tracking-vulnerabilities-leave-millions-of-products-at-risk.html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__ …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, we got to ring in the new year with some major excitement, haven't we? 2018 has met us with a nasty 1-2 punch combination, no doubt! First, the exposure of a vulnerability that effects &lt;code&gt;millions of GPS tracking devices &amp;lt;https://www.csoonline.com/article/3245312/security/gps-tracking-vulnerabilities-leave-millions-of-products-at-risk.html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__. Security researchers were able to access location history, send commands to the device (the same commands that would be sent via SMS), and activate or deactivate geo fencing alarms. All this was said to be possible with no authentication needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was immediately followed up by the Meltdown and Spectre vulnerabilities in what is essentially anything device connected to the internet. From mobile phones, to tablets, to laptop and desktop PCs, these flaws do expose us to some pretty significant risk. But the world is not, in fact, over. Not yet at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;RedLegg &amp;lt;https://www.redlegg.com&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__ team has been fielding calls from clients, friends, and family about these vulnerabilities that have been drawing a lot of attention this week. There is significant implication as to the damage that could result from successful exploit of these issues, but we wanted to present some additional facts for consideration. Here's what we know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meltdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This vulnerability allows any application to access all system memory, including memory allocated for the kernel. Patches are being , and in some cases have been, rolled out and should be applied as soon as possible. So far, research indicates that only Intel chips have been shown to be vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spectre&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This vulnerability allows an application to force another application to access arbitrary portions of its memory, which can then be read through a side channel and affects nearly every CPU built on the x86 architecture. This vulnerability may require changes to processor architecture in order to fully mitigate. According to leading research, this vulnerability impacts Intel, AMD, and ARM chips. Due to the development life-cycle implemented by processor manufacturers, this issue will likely be around for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploitation is possible. Security researchers produced and release proof of concept exploit code within roughly a day. There is no reason to believe that the bad guys will be working feverishly to weaponize these and deploy them for nefarious means. And while there definitely is significant risk associated with these vulnerabilities, there is no proof or reason to believe weaponized exploit code is in use in "the wild".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider taking an inventory of all your systems by processor type, be sure to apply vendor patches as they become available, and track the progress of the updates as they're released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft has issued a patch for Windows 10, while other versions of Windows will be patched on the traditional Patch Tuesday on January 9, 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacOS 10.13.2 mitigates some of the disclosed vulnerabilities, but MacOS 10.13.3 will enhance or complete these mitigations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone using Qualys Vulnerability Management, Qualys will continue to release QIDs for any vendor patches that mitigate this vulnerability. A list of currently-released QIDs is being maintained in this \ &lt;code&gt;Qualys Support article &amp;lt;https://qualys.secure.force.com/articles/How_To/000002746&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an increasingly interesting time to be in the world of security, and an increasingly dangerous time to fall victim. Take the time to read the information that's out there on these issues, there is a lot. But be sure to understand what you're reading. Proof of concept exploits for these issues continue to surface, and with each release the potential for a weaponized exploit increases. Considering the number of devices impacted here, we really need to be watching the horizon as the research develops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year. Stay safe out there!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Security"></category></entry><entry><title>My New Year's Resolution</title><link href="/new-years-resolution.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-03T00:20:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-03T00:20:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Phil Grimes</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-01-03:/new-years-resolution.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;How did we get here?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was enjoying the Christmas holiday with family, a revelation washed over me. My affinity for technology, once a healthy hobby, had devolved into a sick dependency and an addiction. This experience sparked some intense reflection into how I used to love getting my …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;How did we get here?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was enjoying the Christmas holiday with family, a revelation washed over me. My affinity for technology, once a healthy hobby, had devolved into a sick dependency and an addiction. This experience sparked some intense reflection into how I used to love getting my hands on the keyboard and getting online but now the internet is ubiquitous and ingrained into pretty much every aspect of my life. The joy had faded into an expectation and now, when I'm &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; connected, I find myself wondering what's happening. I had to acknowledge that I'd fallen prey to &lt;code&gt;FOMO &amp;lt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear_of_missing_out&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to become more conscious of this over the days since and I started to see how much time I'd spent on some digital device looking at social media. But it was worse. After spending all day with my face in a screen, rather than have conversations over a meal I would thumb through Facebook and continue to evade the human connection. I started to look back on how many times someone would post something on Facebook or @ me on Twitter when we were in the same room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does it happen?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The root of the problem is that we are all, at our base roots, drug addicts. You may not drink. You may not smoke. You may avoid caffeine. But you're human and therefore you're an addict. There are some really great &lt;code&gt;articles &amp;lt;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/brain-wise/201209/why-were-all-addicted-texts-twitter-and-google&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__ which explain this in deeper detail than I'll cover here, but the fact is that we are all driven to seek satisfaction. With the internet, twitter, and texting we now have almost instant gratification of this desire to seek. We no longer have to leave a message on someone's answering machine, wait for them to get home to listen to the message, and wait for a return call. Now you can just shoot a quick text. This increased level of instant gratification can create a dopamine induced loop. The dopamine starts you seeking, which leads to rewarding satisfaction, which sets us on another search. It becomes harder and harder to stop looking at email, stop texting, or stop checking your cell phone to see if you have a message or a new text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, now that I've realized how big this dependency has become, I have to do something about it. And being on an endless quest for knowledge and growth, I've devised a plan to not only break me from my obsession, but to use the opportunity to level up my skills in psychology and situational awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cutting the cord&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in my plan is to delete the social media applications from my phone. Not only will this help to my aim of breaking the compulsion to be connected, but also from the perspective of fewer distractions from the notifications associated and increased battery life on my smartphone. When I saw &lt;code&gt;this tweet &amp;lt;https://twitter.com/iamdevloper/status/947929407318056961&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;__ on the topic, I knew I was on the path to doing something right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Filling the silence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I've been mentally preparing myself for this endeavor, one that I admittedly expect to be quite challenging, I started forcing myself to slowly stop using the phone. When I become conscious that I'm surfing social media, I force myself to put the phone away and reinsert myself into real life. This has helped me to realize how I was getting the added benefit of escaping what was in front of me. Faced with this increased opportunity to engage people I have been enjoying more conversations where there used to be nothing but silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And hacking...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all things, one only takes from an experience what they put in. While this New Year's resolution will certainly allow me to get closer with my friends and family, there is also a more nefarious method to my madness. In my continuing quest to improve my social engineering techniques, I intend to increase my use of various tactics during these random encounters with strangers. While these skills might be used for evil, my intent will be more to exercise my conversational techniques so that I might apply them in the field during penetration testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using conversational signals, and techniques like projection, I'll be working to learn more about how to profile people during random engagements, how to read them on the fly, and how to find the combination of conversational tactics that bring them to a place where I can extract a piece of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I delete these apps from my phone. I'll only be using social media from my laptop, when I'm online and connected. With every day that passes, I feel more and more like I'm living in a society prophesied in the movie Idiocracy. People are simultaneously becoming increasingly harder to deal with and decreasingly smart, and social media on demand only makes it worse. My intention is to learn more about people, learn more about myself, and generally become more present in the moments I have the privilege of experiencing as I navigate the choppy sea of life. Here's to growth and adventure in 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=icmRCixQrx8&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Holidays"></category></entry><entry><title>[u'A Christmas Rant', u'A Christmas Rant']</title><link href="/a-christmas-rant.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-20T11:58:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-12-20T11:58:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Phil Grimes</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-12-20:/a-christmas-rant.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Please allow me to rant for a moment...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was engaged in a conversation recently when I was met with a statement that someone "had to buy me a gift, so it might as well be $thing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O____________________O&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me get one thing absolutely straight, for anyone listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Please allow me to rant for a moment...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was engaged in a conversation recently when I was met with a statement that someone "had to buy me a gift, so it might as well be $thing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O____________________O&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me get one thing absolutely straight, for anyone listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;REQUIRED&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to buy, make, or otherwise procure a gift for me for any reason other than because you want to. I conform to many social conventions to be congenial but I abhor the social requirement of reciprocal gift giving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I haven't impacted your life in a manner significant enough to make you feel like showing your appreciation, don't phone it in. If you haven't come across something that just screams me, save your hard earned money. If you're just buying the biggest canned gift basked that fits within your allotted gift amount because you're obligated, please don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that someone might be forced into giving a gift totally sucks any enjoyment out of receiving said gift for me, as the recipient, and it puts me in a bit of an angry state when the tables are turned. Gifting used to mean something, and sometimes it still does. But more often than not in this consumer driven world, we use stuff as a substitute for substance. It is not!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this doesn't come off as me being a jerk- that is not my intent. But the commercialization of holidays like Christmas have completely destroyed the true meaning and have become disgusting perversions of what they're supposed to mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise, I will get more joy out of spending time with people who matter, disengaging from a pretty much constant work culture, and finding some time to actually relax, than I will in another tie or reindeer boxer shorts or that knock off android tablet that you won from work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAVEAT: Bourbon. Bourbon is always accepted and appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Holidays"></category><category term="Security"></category></entry></feed>